Mike Jacobi

Seattle, Washington, United States

mikerjacobi@gmail.com

425-445-1322

linkedin.com/in/mikerjacobi

https://mike.jagobi.com

Summary

Machine Learning Engineer with over ten years of backend engineering and leadership experience, seeking to support the needs of business and product teams using strong communication and entrepreneurial skills, and deploy mission-critical models and APIs

Experience



Machine Learning Engineer

Charmed

Aug 2023 - Present (4 months)

- Developed text-to-3D Gen AI system using PyTorch/Cuda, deployed as docker images on AWS SageMaker
- Visualized intermediate training artifacts, examined loss calculation, optimized hyperparameters
- · Built 3D object search using Elasticsearch and vector based reranking (Scapy), and systematically measured precision/recall
- Developed APIs to invoke inference models using AWS SAM and Lambdas / S3 / DynamoDB

Senior Engineering Manager

Linden Lab

May 2022 - Aug 2023 (1 year 4 months)

- Managed Backend Team of eight engineers, including planning, prioritizing, hiring, career and technical growth, one-on-ones
- Architected JPMorgan Wallet integration and led cross-org technical calls
- Ensured the production system was responsibly operated and monitored
- · Engaged Product, Finance, Legal, Compliance teams to convert their business requirements into technical designs
- · Worked directly with B2B customers on sales calls and post-contract implementation
- Represented Engineering to Leadership via executive 1:1s and weekly status updates



🚷 Principal Software Engineer

Linden Lab

Jun 2013 - May 2022 (9 years)

- Designed and implemented core FinTech system, which annually facilitated millions of credit card transactions and tens of millions of in-house virtual transactions
- Transitioned backend system to generic multi-tenancy via OAuth2 role based access control
- · Developed foundational microservices of user accounts, financial transactions, and compliance needs using Golang, Python, MySQL
- Created fuzzy PII matching system using Elasticsearch
- · Implemented generic throttle middleware using Redis

Postmasters Student

Los Alamos National Laboratory

2010 - 2013 (3 years)

• Implemented a "smart" filesystem search using FUSE and MongoDB

Education

The University of New Mexico

MS, Computer Science 2011 - 2012

University of Montana

BS, Computer Science 2007 - 2011

Skills

Python • Go (Programming Language) • MySQL • PyTorch • docker • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • AWS Lambda • AWS SageMaker • TypeScript

Honors & Awards

Blastro - Personal Project

2023

- Blastro is a top down, 2D space shooter built in Godot
- · Using the HuggingFace Diffusers library and Stable Diffusion to generate all game assets
- Training enemy movement behavior using reinforcement learning (RL) techniques

Sockhop - Personal Project

2022

- Sockhop is a browser-based video chat app (React, Node / Typescript) where participants can move themselves around a 2D space and play games together
- Try it here: sockhop.me/room/mountains